Guide to the James A. Healy Collection of Irish literature, 1870-1976
Department of Special Collections
- CATALOGUE OF MANUSCRIPT, BOXES 1-16
  - O'GRADY, STANDISH (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Bibliography of O'Grady works, TDc - 1
    - Talbot Press list of O'Grady works, TD - 1
    - Clippings of articles by P. Beaslai, J.M. Flood, and V. Mercier
  - O'KELLY, SEUMAS (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - O'Kelly, Seumas (D) to EAB, 1-12-15., ALS - 4 (2)
    - O'Kelly, Seumas (D) to EAB, 6-30-15., ALS - 4 (3)
    - O'Kelly, Seumas (D) to EAB, 8-26-15., ALS - 2 (3)
    - O'Kelly, Seumas (Kildare) to EAB, 1-6-16., ALS - 4 (3)
  - O'NEILL, EUGENE; O'RIORDAN, CONAL (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - O'Neill, Eugene (NYC) to RC, 1-7-[28]., ANS - 1
    - O'Riordan, Conal (Ealing) to M. Bourgeois, 1-28-13., ALS - 1
    - O'Riordan, Conal (Ealing) to M. Bourgeois, 3-10-13., ALS - 1
    - O'Riordan, Conal (Ealing) to M. Bourgeois, 4-9-13., ALS - 2
  - O'LEARY, JOHN (Box 11, Folder 164)
    - O'Leary, John (NP) to Mr. O'Donoghue, 6-4-[18]92., ALS - 2
    - O'Leary, John (NP) to Mr. O'Donoghue, 2-7-[18]93., ALS - 2
    - O'Leary, John (L) to Mr. O'D[onoghue], 8-16-[18]96., ALS - 2
    - O'Leary, John (D) to [Miltgin?], 1-11-[18]96., ALS - 4
    - O'Leary, John (Rathmines) to Dear Sir, 9-17-[18]85., ALS - 3
    - O'Leary, John (NP) to [Editor of United Irishman], ND., ALS - 1
  - ORPEN, WILLIAM (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Orpen, William, pen and ink sketch, A Song Without Words [depicting Orpen, Tyrell, and OG], ND, (2)
  - O'SHAUGHNESSY, ARTHUR (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - O'Shaughnessy, Arthur ([L]) to Mrs. Kroeker, 12-8-1874., ALS - 4
    - O'Shaughnessy, Arthur (British Museum) to Mrs. Kroeker, 4-10-[1877]., ALS - 3
    - O'Shaughnessy, Arthur (British Museum) to Mrs. Kroeker, 5-15-[18]77., ALS - 2
  - SEAMUS O'SULLIVAN (JAMES STARKEY) (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 2-27-14., ALS - 4
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, 6-2-14., ALS - 2
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, 7-1-14., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, 7-7-14., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, 7-29-14., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 8-13-14., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (Ballymore) to EAB, [October 1914]., ALS - 4
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, [November 1914]., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, [12-5-14]., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 12-24-14., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, [December 1914]., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, [January 1915]., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, 1-8-15., ALS - 4
    - SO'S ([D]) [to EAB], [January 1915]., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, [February 1915]., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 2-2-15., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (NP) to EAB, [March 1915, first letter]., ALS - 2
    - SO'S (NP) to EAB, [March 1915, second letter]., ALS - 2
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 5-19-15., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 5-27-[15]., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, [June 1915, first letter]., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, [June 1915, second letter]., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 6-30-15., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 7-20-15., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 9-16-15., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, 3-6-16., ALS - 3
    - SO'S ([D]) to EAB, ND(I send you...)., ALS - 3
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, ND(I have heard...)., ALS - 4
    - SO'S (Donegal) to EAB, ND(I send on to you)., ALS - 3
    - SO'S (D) to EAB, ND(Many thanks...)., ALS - 3
    - SO'S (Donegal) to EAB, ND(Thanks for your letter...)., ALS - 2
    - SO'S (Donegal) to EAB, ND(Did you ever...)., ALS - 1
    - SO'S (Donegal) to EAB, ND(I wrote...)., ALS - 2
    - [SO'S], signed James Starkey, (D) to JAH, 12-2-38., TLS - 1, enc. list of bibliographies published in Dublin Magazine, TD - 1. Attached is G. Gomma (NYC) to JAH, 11-3-38, ALS - 1
    - SO'S (D) to JAH, 11-7-39., TLS - 4, w/ Tower Press order form and cover
    - SO'S (D) to JAH, 12-27-39., TLS - 1, enc. booklist, TD - 18, w/cov.
  - O'SULLIVAN, SEAN (Box 11, Folder 168)
    Ca. 8 clippings about
  - P (Box 11, Folder 169)
  - PAGE, C.H.; PALMER, HERBERT (Box 11, Folder 170)
    - Page, C.H. (NYC) to AE, 1-30-28., ALS - 3
    - Palmer, Herbert (St. Albans) to SO'S, 6-12-35., ALS - 2
    - Palmer, Herbert (St. Albans) to SO'S, 10-3-37., ALS - 3
    - Palmer, Herbert (St. Albans) to SO'S, Sunday [10-6-35]., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - Palmer, Herbert (St. Albans) to SO'S, Tuesday., ALS - 1
    - Palmer, Herbert (St. Albans) to SO'S, Tuesday., ALS - 2
    - Palmer, Herbert (St. Albans) to AE, Friday., ALS - 1
  - PANKHURST, E. SYLVIA; PARK, M.E. (Box 11, Folder 171)
    - Pankhurst, E. Sylvia (Woodford Green, Essex) to AE, 1-18-30., ALS - 2
    - Park, M. E. (Bryn Mawr) to AE, 2-5-28., ALS - 2
  - PLUNKETT, SIR HORACE (Box 11, Folder 172)
    - Plunkett, Horace (L) to JAH, 11-9-23., ALS - 1
    - Plunkett, Horace (Weybridge) to JAH, 6-4-24., TLS - 1
    - Plunkett, Horace (L) to JAH, 3-26-29., TLS - 1
    - Plunkett, Horace (Weybridge) to OG, 1-14-29., TLS w/a - 3
    - Plunkett, Horace (Weybridge) to RC, 1-17-29., TLS - 3
  - POND, JAMES B.; PRYSE, JAMES M.; PRYSE, JOHN M. (Box 11, Folder 173)
    - Pond, James B. (NYC) to RC, 5-25-32., TLS - 1, enc. draft of announcement for OG's lectures, TDc w/a - 1
    - Pond, James B. (NP) to OG, 5-27-32., TLc - 2
    - Pond, James B. (NYC) to [OG], ND., ANS - 1 w/cov., enc. list of OG's fees, TDc - 1
    - [Pond, James B.] (NP) to J.S. Landers, 8-7-30., TLc - 1
    - Pond, James B. (NYC) to AE, 11-12-27., TLS and TLc - 2
    - Pond, James B. (NYC) to AE, 1-20-28., Telegram - 1
    - Pryse, James M. (Los Angeles) to AE, 1-20-28., TL - 1
    - Pryse, John M. (Los Angeles) to AE, 1-20-28., TLS - 1
  - Q (Box 11, Folder 174)
  - QUILLER-COUCH, SIR ARTHUR (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Quiller-Couch, Arthur (Fowey) to OG, 7-24-39., ALS - 1
  - QUINN, JOHN (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 3-31-15., TLS - 7
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 4-3-15., TLS - 5
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 10-23-15., TLS - 2
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 10-28-15., TLS - 4
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 12-28-15., TLS - 3
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 1-24-16., TLS - 2
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 6-1-17., TLS - 6
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 10-27-17., TLS - 2
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 1-24-18., TLS - 5
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 4-19-18., TLS - 3
    - Quinn, John (NYC) to EAB, 9-12-18., TLS - 3
    - [re John Quinn], extract from Arthur Symons' Confessions, TD - 2, including trans. of extract from Quinn to EAB, 4-19-18
    - 2 clippings re, 1968
  - R (Box 11, Folder 177)
  - REID, FORREST (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 3-26-17., ALS - 2
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 4-14-17., ALS - 1
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 8-2-18., ALS - 3
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, Friday., ALS - 1
    - Reid, Forrest ([Belfast]) to EAB, 9-21-18., TLS w/a - 2
    - Reid, Forrest ([Belfast]) to EAB, 10-19-18., ALS - 6
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 1-3-19., ALS - 3
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 1-6-19., ALS - 2
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 3-5-19., ALS - 2
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, [mid-March 1919]., ALS - 1
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 3-29-19., ALS - 1
    - Reid, Forrest (Belfast) to EAB, 4-10-25., ALS - 2
    - Clipping re death of, 1947
  - ROBINSON, DOROTHY AND LENNOX (Box 11, Folder 179)
    - Robinson, Dorothy (Monkstown) to Dear Sir [JAH], Dec. 1959., TLcS - 1
    - Robinson, Dorothy (Monkstown) to JAH, 3-21-60., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - Robinson, Dorothy (Monkstown) to JAH, 5-9-60., TLS - 1, enc. (1) Robinson, Dorothy to [name left blank], 5-9-60, TL w/a - 1; (2) mimeo. inventory of WBY and LG letters, TD - 12
    - LR (Ardagh) to EAB, 9-27-18., TLS - 1
    - LR (Ardagh) to EAB, 9-30-[18]., TLS - 1
    - LR (Co. Dublin) to EAB, 12-19-22., TLS - 1
    - LR (Co. Dublin) to EAB, 1-13-23., TLS - 1
    - LR (D) to OG, Tuesday [1949]., TL - 1
    - LR (D) to JAH, 1-17-47., TLS - 2
    - LR (D) to JAH, 1-31-47(one of two letters)., TLS - 2
    - LR (D) to JAH, 1-31-47(one of two letters)., TLS - 1. Probable enclosure: copies of Hayes to Robinson, ND, and Nolan to Hayes, ND, TD - 1
    - LR (D) to JAH, 3-29-47., TLS - 1
    - LR (D) to JAH, 4-18-47., TLS - 1
    - LR (D) to JAH, 4-26-47., TLS - 1
    - LR (NP) to ECY, [5-13-38]., APCS - 1
    - LR (D) to ECY, 4-3-?., ALS - 1
    - JAH's correspondence with booksellers re books from LR's estate
    - Clippings re death of LR, 1958 - ca. 8
  - ROLLESTON, T.W. (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - Rolleston, T.W. (Hampstead) to M. Bourgeois, 4-18-13., ALS - 2
    - Rolleston, T.W. (Hampstead) to M. Bourgeois, 4-28-13., ALS - 1
  - RUSSELL, ANNA (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - AR (Fort Ogden) to JAH, 10-28-68., APCS - 1
    - AR (Fort Ogden) to JAH, 12-23-68., APCS - 1
  - RUSSELL, DIARMUID (Box 11, Folder 182)
    - Russell, Diarmuid (Lake Forest, I11.) to [RC], 8-27-[35]., ALS - 1
    - Russell, Diarmuid, 3 letters of recommendation concerning, 1924., Trans: TL - 3
  - AE to AYRES, BOURGEOIS, and BOWERS (Box 11, Folder 183)
    - [AE] (NP) to H.M. Ayres, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (Donegal) to M. Bourgeois, [1913]., ALS - 2
    - [AE] (NP) to Claude G. Bowers, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
  - AE to ERNEST A. BOYD (Box 11, Folder 184)
    - AE (D) to EAB, Sept. 1912., ALS - 1
    - AE (Donegal) to EAB, [6-5-13]., ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to EAB, 1-15-14., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 3-14-14[inadvertently written as 1913]., ALS - 4 (1) and partial trans.
    - AE (D) to EAB, 4-20-14., ALS - 4 and partial trans.
    - AE (D) to EAB, 6-5-14., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 7-13-1[4]., ALS - 4 and partial trans.
    - AE (D) to EAB, 10-12-14., ALS - 6
    - AE (D) to EAB, 12-27-14., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 2-9-15., ALS - 6
    - AE (D) to EAB, 4-12-15., ALS - 4 [fragile]
    - AE (NP) to EAB, Tuesday 6 July [1915?]., ALS - 1
    - AE (Plunkett House) to EAB, Oct. 1915., ALS - 6 [fragile]
    - AE (D) to EAB, [Jan. 1916]., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, 6-9-16., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - AE (D) to EAB, 8-1-16., ALS - 4
    - [AE] (L) to EAB, cover postmarked 10-22-18.
      [JAH annotated this cover, found in a folder of miscellaneous items, George Moore, but the hand is AE's.]
    - AE ([D]) to EAB, 7-9-19., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, Wednesday 191?., ALS - 1 [enclosed WBY (L) to AE, 4-17-?, ANS - 2: now placed in WBY Folder]
    - [AE?] (Sandgate, Kent) to EAB, cover postmarked 4-3-20
    - AE (D) to EAB, 8-25-20., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 11-11-20., ALS - 6
    - AE (D) to EAB, 4-21-21., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 5-19-21., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, 8-3-21., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 12-24-21., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, 1-24-22., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 5-25-22., ALS - 4
    - AE ([Cork]) to EAB, 6-19-22., ALS - 6
    - AE (D) to EAB, 1-3-23., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, 1-10-23., ALS - 1
    - AE (Cork) to EAB, 6-14-23., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 5-13-24., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, 5-25-24., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 11-19-24., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, 12-4-25., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - AE (D) to EAB, 6-14-33., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, Friday, As your time is short..., ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to EAB, ND, I have been wrapt round..., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, ND, I do hope the IAOS..., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, Wednesday, I am glad..., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, Monday [191?], Everyting is..., ALS - 4
    - AE (Plunkett House) to EAB, Whitmonday., ALS - 6
    - AE (D) to EAB, Friday, The Homestead..., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, Tuesday [191?], I found a copy..., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, ND, Don't misunderstand me..., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to EAB, Tuesday, I am just back..., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, ND, I am sorry..., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to EAB, ND, I don't know whether..., ALS - 1
    - AE to William Byrne, see AE to William Dara
  - AE TO RICHARD CAMPBELL (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-13-23., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 3-30-26., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 10-19-27., Telegram - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 10-21-27., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 10-28-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-1-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-8-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-11-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-15-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-18-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-22-27., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-25-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-29-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-2-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-28-27., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 1-3-28., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 5-10-28., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 5-22-28., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 6-1-28., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 6-5-28., TLS w/a - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 7-13-28., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 7-17-28., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-27-28., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-5-28., ALS - 2 and trans.
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-11-28., TLS - 2 and trans. (2)
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-14-28., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-17-28., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-21-28., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-28-28., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 1-15-29., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 1-22-29., TLS - 3
    - AE (D) to RC, 2-6-29., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 2-12-29., TLS - 3
    - AE (D) to RC, 2-19-29., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 2-20-29., ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 2-21-29., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 2-26-29., TLS w/a - 3 and trans.
    - AE (D) to RC, 3-5-29., TLS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 3-12-29., TLS - 3 and trans.
    - AE (D) to RC, 3-19-29., TLS w/a - 3
    - AE (D) to RC, 3-26-29., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-2-29., TLS w/a - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-9-29., TLS - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-30-29., TLS - 3
    - AE (D) to RC, 8-2-29., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 8-15-29., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 9-13-29., TLS - 3
    - AE (D) to RC, 10-31-29., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-28-29., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 1-3-30., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 1-23-30., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 1-27-30., ALS - 4 and trans.
    - AE (D) to RC, 2-20-20 [for 1930]., ALS - 4 and trans.
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-11-[30]., TLS - 2 and trans. (2)
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-22-30., Trans: TLc - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 7-15-30., Trans.: TL - 1
    - AE (D) to RC, 8-2230., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 5-24-31., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 5-28-31., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 7-25-31., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 8-11-31., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 11-16-31., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-14-31., ALS with sketches - 3 (1)
    - AE (D) to RC, 3-5-32., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-1-32., ALS with sketch - 5
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-8-32., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-28-32., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 8-14-32., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, [Dec. 1932]., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-5-32., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 12-16-32., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 4-4-33., ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to RC, 5-30-33., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to RC, 6-18-33., ALS - 4 and trans. (2)
    - AE (L) to RC, 8-28-33., ALS - 3
    - AE (L) to RC, 1-1-34., ALS with sketch - 2 and partial trans. (1)
    - AE (Donegal) to RC, 5-23-34., ALS with sketches - 6 and partial trans.
    - AE (L) to RC, 9-21-34., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - AE (L) to RC, 10-31-34., ALS - 2
    - AE (L) to RC, 11-3-34., ALS - 1
    - AE (L) to RC, 11-12-34., ALS - 4 w/cov. and trans. (2)
    - AE (L) to RC, 12-4-34., ALS - 2
    - AE (L) to RC, 12-9-34., ALS - 2
    - AE ([Washington]) to RC, [12-31-34]., ALS - 2
    - AE (Washington) to RC, 1-7-35., ALS - 2
    - AE (Washington) to RC, 1-9-35., ALS - 2
    - AE (Washington) to RC, [1-20-35]., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - AE (Washington) to RC, 1-23-35., ALS - 1
    - AE (Washington) to RC, 1-30-35(first letter)., ALS - 1
    - AE (Washington) to RC, 1-30-35(second letter)., ANS - 1
    - AE (Washington) to RC, Tuesday [?Jan.-Feb. 1935]., ALS - 2
    - AE (Washington) to RC, [?Jan.-Feb. 1935]., ALS - 2
    - AE (Washington) to RC, [2-21-35]., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - AE (NYC) to RC, 2-25-35., ALS - 1
    - AE (L) to RC, 3-14-35., ALS - 3
    - AE (L) to RC, 5-24-35., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - AE (Bournemouth) to RC, 7-5-35., Pc of ALS - 1 (4) and trans.
  - AE to CARTER, F.; CARTER, H; CRAIG, A.T.; DARA, WILLIAM; and DELBOS, C.E. (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - AE (D) to Frederick Carter, [191?]., ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to Huntley Carter, 11-19-16., ALS - 1 and auction notice
    - AE (D) to Huntley Carter, [1916]., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to Huntley Carter, 7-4-20., Trans: TL -1
    - [AE] (NP) to Anne T. Craig, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (D) to William Dara [pseudonym of William Byrne], ND., ALS - 2 and partial trans. Also printed text in AE Replies to a Critic in Irish Independent, 6-9-39 (3)
    - AE (D) to William Dara, ND., ALS - 5 and partial trans. Also printed text as above
    - [AE] (NP) to C. Edmund Delbos, 2-6-28., TNc - 1
  - AE to LORD DUNSANY (Box 12, Folder 187)
    - AE (D) to D, 2-3-08., ALS - 2 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, Friday 1908., ALS - 1 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, [190?]., ALS - 1 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, [191?]., ALS - 2 (7)
    - AE (Plunkett House) to D, ND, I am sorry..., ALS - 2 (7)
    - AE (Plunkett House) to D, ND, I have had a few copies..., ALS - 1 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, ND, I am sorry I will not be able to accept..., ALS - 1 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, Saturday., ALS - 2 (7)
    - AE (Plunkett House) to D, ND., ALS - 3 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, 5-10-19., ALS - 2 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, 4-11-32., ALS - 2 (7)
    - AE (D) to D, 1-24-33., Pc of ALS with sketch - 2 (4)
    - AE (D) to D, 4-5-34., Pc of ALS with sketch - 2 (4)
  - AE to FINLEY, J.; OLIVER ST. JOHN GOGARTY; GOLDRING, D.; GOLDRING, L.; GOODWILLY, MARY C. (Box 12, Folder 188)
    - AE (D) to John Finley, 2-1-29., Trans: TLc - 2
    - AE (D) to OG, 12-3-23., Trans: TL - 1 (1)
    - AE (D) to OG, Wednesday, I thought you were away!, ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to OG, ND, James Stephens..., ALS - 1, w/a on verso inscribing it as gift from OG to JAH, w/cov.
    - AE (D) to [Douglas] Goldring, [12-21-18]., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - AE (D) to Louis Goldring, 3-27-19., Trans. from reprinted letter in Goldring's Odd Man Out: TL - 1
    - [AE] (NP) to Mary C. Goodwilly, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
  - AE to IRENE HAUGH (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - AE (Ballymore) to IH, [summer 1929], I hope you are not overworked..., ALS - 1(3)
    - AE (Ballymore) to IH, [Summer 1929], I am sorry..., ALS - 1 (3)
    - AE (Ballymore) to IH, Wednesday [summer 1929], How nice of you..., ALS - 4 with 2 sketches (3)
    - AE (Ballymore) to IH, 7-6-29., Envelope for one of 3 preceding letters listed here, annotated by IH
    - AE (Ballymore) to IH, [summer 1929?], I am glad to know that..., ALCS - 1
    - AE (D) to IH, 8-1-29., ALS with sketch - 1 (2)
    - AE (D) to IH, [after August 1929]., ALS with sketches - 2 (3), enc. in IH's envelope annotated by her and JAH
    - AE (D) to IH, 6-3-30., ALS - 1 (3)
    - AE (D) to IH, 7-8-30., ALS with sketch - 3 (3) w/cov.
    - AE (D) to IH, [7-15-30]., ALS with sketches - 2 (8) w/cov.
    - AE (Liverpool) to IH, [9-13-30]., ALCS - 2 (5)
    - AE (Davenport, Iowa) to IH, [10-15-30]., ALS - 5 (5) w/cov.
    - AE (Moscow, Idaho) to IH, 11-4-30., ALS - 2 (5) w/cov.
    - AE (San Francisco) to IH, 11-26-30., ALS - 4 (4) w/cov. and partial trans.
    - AE (Waco, Texas) to IH, 12-13-30., ALS - 4 (6) w/cov.
    - AE (Long Island) to IH, 12-23-30., ALS - 2 (5) w/cov.
    - AE (NP) to IH, Christmas 1931.Christmas card sketch w/ ANS -, 1
    - AE (D) to IH, Sunday., ALS - 1 (5)
    - [AE (NP) to IH, ND]. Ink and crayon sketch of Child with halo -, 1
    - [AE (NP) to IH, ND]. Brown crayon sketch of seated girl -, 1
    - [AE (NP) to IH, ND]. Small ink and crayon sketches of landscape and fireplaces, signed George Russell -, 2
  - PHOTOCOPIES OF PREVIOUS FOLDER, AE to IH (Box 12, Folder 189A)
  - AE to KIPLING, R.; LAPPIN, H.A.; LOWELL, A.L.; MACKENNA, S.; MANNING, M.; MARTYN, E.; MORRIS, L.R.; MOSHER, T.B.; MUMFORD, L.; O'LEARY; PRIESTLY; RITTENHOUSE; RUMSEY, M.H.; SHAW, MRS. G.B.; SQUIRE, J.C. (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - AE (NP) to Rudyard Kipling, [1919].Reprinted in Eire Bulletin, 4-28-58,from the New York Globe, 1919
    - [AE] (NP) to Henry A. Lappin, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - [AE] (NP) to Abbott L. Lowell, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (D) to Stephen [MacKenna], 7-10-25., TLS - 1
    - [AE] (NP) to Mary Manning, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (D) to [Edward] Martyn, 7-28-1899., ANS - 1
    - AE (D) to Lloyd R. Morris, [4-30-14]., ALS - 3 w/cov.
    - AE (D) to T. B. Mosher, 5-14-10., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to T. B. Mosher, [6-13-10]., ALS - 2
    - [AE] (NP) to Lewis Mumford, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (D) to O'Leary, 2-18-1897., Pc of ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to Priestly [i.e. J.B. Priestley?], Monday., Pc of ALS - 4
    - AE (D) to Miss Rittenhouse, 10-9-23., ALS - 2
    - AE (L) to Mary [Harriman Rumsey], 10-31-34., ALS - 2
    - AE (L) to?, 8-28-33., Trans. of extract of letter about Mary Rumsey: TLc - 1
    - AE (NP) to Mrs. G. B. Shaw, 12-11-28., TLcS w/a - 3
    - AE (D) to [J.C.] Squire, 8-22-19., ALS - 2 and trans.
  - AE to JAMES STEPHENS and MRS. JAMES STEPHENS (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - AE (D) to James Stephens, 9-1-26., ALS - 1 (1)
    - AE (D) to James Stephens, 5-8-28., ALS - 1 (1)
    - AE (D) to James Stephens, [Feb. 1929.], ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to James Stephens, Monday [late 1931?]., ALS - 2 (1)
    - AE (D) to James Stephens, Friday [Oct. -Nov. 1931?]., ALS - 1 (1)
    - AE (D) to James Stephens, [1931?], It is delightful and sad..., ALS - 2 (1)
    - AE (L) to James Stephens, 1-29-34., ALS - 1 (1)
    - AE (L) to James Stephens, 3-2-34., ALS - 2 (1)
    - AE (L) to James Stephens, Monday., ALS - 1 (1)
    - AE (D) to James Stephens, Wednesday., ALS - 1 (1)
    - AE (L) to Mrs. James Stephens, [8-5-33]., APCS - 1 (1)
  - AE to WADIS, B.P.; WALLACE, HENRY; WARREN, M.R.; WELLS; WILLIAM, M.; WILSON, M.L. (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - [AE] (NP) to B. P. Wadis, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (L) to Henry [Wallace?], 4-23-35., Pc of ALS - 2
    - AE (Illinois) to Henry [Wallace], [Jan. 1935]., Pc of ALS - 4
    - AE (Bournemouth) to Henry [Wallace], 7-15-35., Pc of TL, signed A.E. p.p. Pamela Travers - 1
    - [AE] (NP) to Maude R. Warren, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (D) to Mr. Wells, 11-1-26., TNS - 1
    - AE (D) to Mr. Wells, 6-8-30., ALS - 1
    - AE (Donegal) to Mr. Wells, 6-17-30., ALS - 3
    - [AE] (NP) to Maurice William, 2-6-28., TLc - 1
    - AE (L) to [M.L.] Wilson, 3-17-35., Trans: TL - 1
  - AE to ELIZABETH CORBET YEATS (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - AE (D) to ECY, 1-7-21., ALS - 4. Annotated clipping of his poem Brixton Prison pasted on first page; encloses tearsheet of Michael from The Irish Statesman, 12-20-19
    - AE (D) to ECY, 1-8-21., ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to ECY, 4-6-32., ALS - 2 and trans.
    - AE (D) to ECY, Good Friday [1932]., ALS - 2 and trans.
    - AE (D) to ECY, 4-20-36., ALS - 2 and trans.
    - AE (D) to ECY, 12-18-32., ALS - 2
    - AE (D) to ECY, Tuesday., ALS - 1
    - AE (D) to ECY, ND., ALS - 1
  - AE: MISCELLANEOUS WRITINGS BY (1) (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - AE (NP), ND,untitled poem, Had thine art not skill to change., ADS - 1 (1)
      [N.B. this is written on OG's headed stationery, showing a swan holding the wand of Aesculapius, and the 15 Ely Place address.]
    - AE (NP), ND,poem, A Dream., TDS w/a - 1
    - AE (NP), photograph of poem, Mother and Children, 1-15-24., ADS - 1
    - [AE] (NP), sketch of reclining figure on verso of [fragment of?] poem, Cast off its tawdry coating, ND., Pc of AD - 2
    - AE, article, Leading Figures in Modern Irish Art, Times March 24th., TD - 2
    - AE, clipping, The Post Impressionists: Art and Barbarism, 1-26-11
    - AE, clipping of poem, Ares, ND., Autograph annotation and signature
    - AE, clipping of poem, A European Litany, ND., 2 copies, one with autograph signature
    - AE, clipping of poem, Shadows and Lights, Times Literary Supplement, 1-28-15., 3 copies, one with autograph signature and annotations
    - AE, clipping of poem, Gods of War [ The Times, 9-30-14].
    - AE, clipping of poem, Apocalyptic, [ The New Age, 9-9-15]
    - Ae, clipping of poem, Promise. JAH's note hazards date of ca. 1918